crystal2cross@gmail.com (323) 316-5220 crystal2cross.com

SUMMARY

With an engineer's mind, artist's eye, and empathetic heart, I am a designer who champions for great user experiences.

PORTFOLIO

Lead Designer & Developer, Coalition on Homelessness | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/coh.html

Designed and implemented a responsive website for an organization working to address the root causes of homelessness and poverty in San Francisco. The project focus was on information architecture, visual design, and responsive design.

Lead Designer & Developer, Street Sheet | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/streetsheet.html

Designed and implemented a responsive website for a biweekly San Francisco newspaper that is an extension of their print newspaper, archiving all articles with additional web-only content and optimized for reading on all screen sizes.

UX Designer, Homes.com | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/homeshare.html

Designed a companion website for Homes.com to help people who can't afford to buy a home, find and meet people to join forces and buy their dream home with. Deliverables included personas, journey maps, wireframes, and click-through prototype.

UX Designer, Progress Hardware | View Case Study: http://crystal2cross.github.io/progress-hardware.html

Designed an ecommerce website for a brick and mortar hardware store. Deliverables included navigation system, streamlined checkout process, wireframes, and click-through prototype.

SKILLS

UX: Information Architecture, User Research, Personas, Rapid Prototyping, Wireframes, Usability Testing

Tools: Sketch3, InVision, Paper Prototyping

Technical: HTML, CSS (Sass), JavaScript (AngularJS, Backbone.Marionette), Java, Scala, PHP, Git

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

General Assembly, User Experience Design Immersive

March 2016 - May 2016

Coursera, www.coursera.org

Courses completed with certification:

Human-Centered Design, License VQX4TZT6FEUA Design Principles, License GGX4A2JXRUPQ

Social Computing, License EA7JYQX9Q2XJ Input and Interaction, License ZVHYP6MCTLU9

Lynda, www.lynda.com

Courses completed with certification:

WordPress: Building Themes from Scratch Using Underscores, License 3F0349

WordPress: Developing with Sass and Grunt, js, License E2B9DF

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Designer & Developer

May 2016 - Present

Software Engineer | AppDirect | www.appdirect.com

April 2015 - February 2016

AppDirect is a cloud service commerce platform provider enabling people to create, find, buy and manage software in the cloud. As a member of multiple engineering teams, I helped to: develop AppDirect's OAuth management panel; design and implement a themed partner marketplace for Hawaiian Telecom; and troubleshoot issues and bugs for existing partners. Technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS (Sass), Backbone.Marionette, and Java.

Web Application Developer | Sungevity | www.sungevity.com

June 2014 - April 2015

Sungevity is a solar power provider helping the world run on the sun. As a member of multiple engineering teams, I helped to develop their customer portal and Instant IQuote (IIQ) iPad web application. Developing for IIQ, I was responsible for the user flow and interface of the application, and development was iterative, with real-time feedback from field members using the app in Lowes hardware stores and at Sungevity marketing events. Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery Mobile, AngularJS, Scala, Play (Scala Web Framework), and PHP.

Mobile Web Developer Internship | Moovweb | www.moovweb.com

March 2014 - June 2014

Moovweb is a platform enabling businesses to transform their desktop-only websites to mobile and tablet experiences. As a member of a 3-person developer team, we transformed Forever21's website utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS (Sass), and various JavaScript libraries including jQuery, Tritium, and Uranium.

EDUCATION

B.A. in Computer Science at University of California, San Diego (UCSD)

Class of 2013